ccfa.org 2019-06-24

# Crohn's & Colitis Foundation's Privacy Policy | Crohn's & Colitis Foundation

The purpose of the Crohn's & Colitis Foundation website is to provide information about the Foundation and Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IBD) to people living with Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis, as well as to their families and friends; healthcare professionals; and the general public.

### What information do we collect and how do we use it?

You may browse our website without identifying yourself or providing any personally identifiable information. When you interact with us through your computer, however, we do record certain non-identifying site-usage data, such as your number of visits to our website pages. 

If you elect to donate, register for an event, or sign up for any of our publications, you will be asked to provide personal information such as your name, address, city, state, zip, phone number, and email address. 

We may use this information to communicate with you by email or postal mail from time to time. The Crohn's & Colitis Foundation keeps all names, addresses, and all other personal information supplied by participants of our website strictly confidential. The Foundation discourages sharing of personal information in public online forums. Please keep in mind, however, that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information on message boards, through email, or in chat areas, that information may be collected and used by others. We may receive confirmation via HTML code when you open an email from us, which helps us measure our reach and ensure reduce or eliminate duplicate e-mails. If you no longer wish to receive e-mails from us, please unsubscribe or change your profile settings.

Some parts of our website may also use 'cookies,' which are alphanumeric identifiers that are transferred to your computer through your web browser. You may configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is sent. However if cookies are rejected, some pages on our website may not function properly.

Please note: Children under the age of 13 should receive parental consent prior to disclosing any personal information.

When you interact with us, we use technological tools such as "Cookies," "Log Data," and other identifiers to receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with our site. Examples include your IP address, unique device identifiers, session ids, computer or mobile device make and model, operating system, browser program and version, pages you requested and history. We may use this data to, among other things, tailor, customize and enhance services as well as your experience and to help diagnose, operate and administer our site. We also use cookies to save you time while using the Websites, remind us who you are, and track and target user interests in order to provide a customized experience. Cookies allow us to collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information from you, like which pages and applications you visited and what links you clicked on. Use of this information helps us to create a more user-friendly experience for all visitors. You may configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is sent. However if cookies are rejected, some pages on our website may not function properly.

Our site may automatically collect usage information, such as the numbers and frequency of visitors to our website and their components. This data is only used in the aggregate, that is, as a statistical measure, and not in a manner that would identify you personally. We use this information to design and improve our sites, and may provide this information to partners so they can understand how often users use areas of our websites.

When you visit our website, we may automatically collect certain information through the use of electronic tools like Cookies and Web beacons or Pixel tags. We use Non-Personally Identifiable Information to troubleshoot, administer our site, analyze trends, gather demographic and engagement information, enhance and customize our site, measure the effectiveness of our links, content and programming, comply with applicable law, and cooperate with law enforcement activities. We may also share this information with our authorized third-party service providers,

We may receive confirmation via HTML code when you open an email from us, which helps us measure our reach and ensure reduce or eliminate duplicate e-mails. If you no longer wish to receive e-mails from us, please unsubscribe or change your profile settings.

### Do we share your information?

The Crohn's & Colitis Foundation keeps your personal information strictly confidential. However, we may occasionally make our constituent's names and addresses available to other reputable healthcare non-profit organizations. Your name is only available to these organizations for a limited time and your information will not be directly associated with the Foundation. Your information will not be readily accessible to other organizations unless you choose to respond to their initial mailing. We DO NOT share email addresses or other health-related data. To opt-out from donor mailing address list sharing that the Foundation may participate in with other organizations, email us at [info@crohnscolitisfoundation.org](mailto:info@crohnscolitisfoundation.org) with the request “Do Not Share” in the subject line or message (please include the mailing address) or call us at 1-800-932-2423 to have us update the record.

For disclosure of demographic information (e.g., rental or exchange of donor lists with other organizations), the Foundation as a minimum will use an "opt-out" approach. An "opt-out" is obtained when an individual declines or "opts-out" of disclosures to third parties or from receiving any communication from the organization. You may opt-out at any time to cease receiving communications from the Foundation; If an individual does not opt-out, permission is deemed granted.

### What security do we provide to protect your personal information?

The Crohn's & Colitis Foundation uses multiple electronic and administrative safeguards to protect your information from unauthorized access, such as firewall technologies and Secure Socket Layer (SSL) security, (described below). Access to your account information is protected via system passwords which are changed periodically. Despite use of these safeguards, we cannot guarantee and do not represent that your information will always be secure from unauthorized access.

### Do we provide a secure environment for online transactions?

All credit card information collected through online transactions are processed with SSL security, an established protocol for transmitting information via the Internet which uses server authentication and data encryption to ensure that your data is safe, secure, and available only to authorized staff members of the Foundation. 

### Choices under EU law

If your Personal Information is subject to the protections offered by EU law, you may:

  * Access, correct, update or request deletion of your Personal Information, at any time by contacting us using the contact details provided on our site;
  * Object to processing of your Personal Information, ask us to restrict processing of your Personal Information or request portability of your Personal Information;
  * Withdraw your consent at any time if we have collected and process your Personal Information with your consent;

To exercise any of these rights please contact us. Please note that if you are not subject to EU law, these rights do not apply to you.

### How can you contact us to review or correct your personal information?

You may view or edit your personal profile by logging in to our website at www.crohnscolitisfoundation.org, where you can also view a history of your online transactions or subscribe to our e-newsletter. In addition, you may also email us at [info@crohnscolitisfoundation.org](mailto:info@crohnscolitisfoundation.org) or call us at 1-800-932-2423 to review your personal information.

### Disclaimer on information provided on the Crohn's & Colitis Foundation website

All articles and messages that appear in our website, including notes from physicians and other Crohn's & Colitis Foundation designated participants, are provided for general information purposes only. They do not represent individual medical advice, counsel concerning individual treatments or medical care, referrals to healthcare professionals, or any other recommendations. You should not rely on any information on these pages to replace consultations with your doctor and other qualified healthcare professionals regarding your individual health needs. Statements or opinions expressed by physicians and other independent authors reflect the views of each such individual and do not necessarily reflect the views or any official policy of the Foundation. 

The Crohn's & Colitis Foundation makes every effort to provide accurate and up-to-date information. However, the Foundation expressly disclaims all responsibility and liability arising from your use of or reliance on this website or for the information contained herein as a reference source, and for any advice or other guidance or information provided by any health care provider contributing to this site. 

Except where otherwise noted, all information on the Crohn's & Colitis Foundation website, including its design and organization, is copyrighted by the Crohn's & Colitis Foundation. This material is for personal use only. Permission to otherwise reprint or electronically reproduce any document in whole or in part is expressly prohibited, unless prior written consent is obtained from the Crohn's & Colitis Foundation.  

The Foundation's website also contains information copyrighted and owned by entities and individuals other than the Foundation. This information is for personal use only. Permission to otherwise reprint or electronically reproduce any document in whole or in part is expressly prohibited, unless prior written consent is obtained from the owner.  

The Foundation's website also contains third party information. Whenever possible, such information is marked with the name of the source and does not necessarily represent the opinion of the Crohn's & Colitis Foundation. We do not take any responsibility whatsoever for such third party information. 

The Foundation's website also contains links to other Internet sites. The Foundation does not necessarily endorse the views expressed in the Internet sites to which it provides links, nor is the organization responsible for the information they contain. The content of these linked sites are the sole responsibility of such sites and their contributing authors. The Crohn's & Colitis Foundation does not intend links to other sites to be referrals or endorsements of the linked entities, but rather provides such links for convenience only.

The Crohn's & Colitis Foundation maintains the right to modify this privacy policy at any time by electronic notice posted on our website. Your continued use of our website after the date that such notice is posted will be deemed to be your agreement to the changed terms.
